Sergio I. Escamilla

Oakland, CA | (510) 457-5495 | siescamilla@ucdavis.edu | https://www.linkedin.com/in/sergio-i-e-91b0013b/

Profile

Professional CRM and Marketing specialist with over 6+ years of experience developing and launching end-to-end campaign strategies for clients across multiple industries such in; Fintech, Real Estate, Ecommerce, and HealthCare. I've developed and deployed thousands of email journeys and have generated \$50+ million in email attributable revenue. Experienced with Salesforce Marketing Cloud, Hubspot and other CRM tools.

Experience

CRM AND DATABASE MARKETING MANAGER | INVENTIVE DESIGN | MAY 2018 TO PRESENT

- Deploy testing strategies to identify and minimize friction across all customer touchpoints to drive higher opt-in rates and improve conversion rates.
- Build and share weekly KPI reports around channel performance and test results to cascade actionable data and insights throughout the organization.
- Create and maintain the monthly campaign calendar, the CRM quarterly and annual roadmap and CRM test-and-learn calendar in order to ensure my team's daily tactical efforts are supporting the overarching long-term needs and goals of the business.

MARKETING MANAGER | MY DIGITAL MONEY | JAN 2021 TO OCT 2021 (CONTRACT)

- · Managed and created company website, blog updates, copywriting material.
- · Built landing pages using the highest web design industry standards.
- · Implemented CRM automation journeys using Salesforce Marketing Cloud.
- · Created email triggers for customer form signups.
- · Managed paid ads campaigns on platforms such as; Google Ads, Facebook, Microsoft, etc.
- · Spearheaded multi-department projects and collaborated with outsourced talent to achieve desired results.

CRM AUTOMATION SPECIALIST | METROPOLITAN TRANSPORTATION COMMISSION | NOV 2017 TO MAY 2018 (CONTRACT)

- · Implemented CRM communications channels with multiple agency contractors.
- · Designed, tested and launched email campaigns for MTC's newsletter subscribers.
- Trained both agency and contractor staff on how to effectively use the Salesforce Marketing Cloud and Sales Cloud CRM platform.
- · Designed data driven reports to be used by agency staff.

CRM MARKETING MANAGER | NOBLE GOLD INVESTMENTS | JAN 2017 TO OCT 2017 (CONTRACT)

- · Implemented CRM communications channels with multiple agency contractors.
- · Designed, tested and launched email campaigns for MTC's newsletter subscribers.
- Trained both agency and contractor staff on how to effectively use the Salesforce Marketing Cloud and Sales Cloud CRM platform.
- · Designed data driven reports to be used by agency staff.

MARKETING AND OPERATIONS MANAGER | M-GO | JUN 2011 TO DEC 2016

- · Deployed multi-channel marketing campaigns with a strong focus on customer acquisition and retention.
- · Built automated marketing emails with customization based on unique customer data and preferences.
- · Weekly A/B testing and reporting to continually refine and iterate email newsletters.
- · High volume user segmentation with customized messaging.
- Managed the scale of our email list from only a few thousand to several million subscribers within 1.5 years across different ESPs such as Exact Target and Bronto.

Education

BACHELOR OF ARTS IN INTERNATIONAL RELATIONS | UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, DAVIS DAVIS, CA

Skills & Abilities

- · Sales Force
- JavaScript
- · SQL

- · Project Management
- · B2C Marketing
- Analytics

Activities and Interests

Technology, environmental conservation, chess, art, hiking, travel